Vivek Singh Pune, India

System Engineer: Infosys

+91 8826915637 | vivek.singh.6967@gmail.com | Linkdin:Vivek Singh | GITHUB:Vivek Singh

Summary

System Engineer at Infosys, a software developer focused on providing the best possible and feasible solution for Business requirements. Involved across teams for Business Solutions, Data Analytics & Strategy Planning for Roadmaps and Solutions.

Skill and Strengths

Python (Django, NumPy, Panda, TensorFlow: RASA)

NodeJS (Express JS, Basic React JS) MongoDB)

Data Analytics & Problem-Solving

Databases(Oracle, MongoDB, MySQL)

- > Experienced with various stages of Business meetings regarding product improvements and creating most feasible and optimum logic to attain the requirement under least possible bucket size.
- > Strong Analytical & Data Mining skills with the ability to quickly derive at a conclusion using Data Points
- > Strong with Data Structures and algorithms construction.

Experience

SYSTEM ENGINEER, Infosys, Pune, Maharashtra

July, 2018 - Today

- Participated in all phases of the system development life cycle, from requirements analysis to implementation.
- Monitored and tested application performance to identify potential bottlenecks, develop solutions, and collaborate with developers on solution implementation.
- Defined enterprise processes and best practices and tailored enterprise processes for applications.

INTERN, Infosys, Pune, Maharashtra

Jan, 2018 - JUNE, 2018

 Involved in creating the methods of the Data Access Layer and Database design from scratch for a client project, regularly monitoring the application development and functioning through data driven approach for improving the current deployment fundamentals.

Educations

B. Tech, CSE with specialization in Cloud Computing and Virtualization

Galgotias University, 2014 - 2018

Extracurriculars

• Co-developer of 2 indie Games for Windows OS titled:

1. Star EV 2. RGB WARS

- Excellent communication skills and experience of Client interaction during various College and Internship events.
- Regular participant of various coding challenges online.
- Represented School & College in Debates, Extempore & various other events.